

Justin Barnhill 200 Montclair Circle, Oxford, AL 36203 205-508-0882 justindbarnhill@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/justindbarnhill/

Self-motived engineer with over twenty years of industry experience interested in opportunities to join an organization using emerging technologies to increase my skillset while leveraging my knowledge and work ethic to improve customer satisfaction, increase productivity, and contribute to accomplishing business objectives as efficiently as possible.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sustaining Engineer, Idemia

October 2010 - present

Provide support, new client deployment, and maintenance for a proprietary SQL based testing platform utilized for driver testing in approximately twenty four states and several foreign nations. Differentiate between usage errors and programming bugs to aid development in future improvements and upgrades. Identify potential training issues to be addressed by the proper personnel (either internal or client as contracts dictate). Interface, via phone and email, with IT personnel in multiple states with various environments ranging from Windows based server environments to Linux based to identify root cause of recurring issues atypical of similar deployments. Support testing platform on multiple Windows based client machines and with all versions of SQL from 2000 to current along with AWS hosted environments. Utilize virtual environments for testing and troubleshooting as well as automate maintenance procedures to verify customer data integrity. Develop internal maintenance procedures to streamline data integrity. Verify SLA is met in regards to initial contact, field level repairs, and contact with state managed helpdesk and internal helpdesk to insure corrective actions take place in a timely manner. Give instruction via phone to non-technical personnel to repair mission critical components when remote connectivity is not an option. Assist client personnel with generating usage reports, error log reports, and other reports as requested for upper level management. Also assist sales personnel in generating reports and statistics for case use scenarios and aid in client side demos during sales meetings. Design and develop integration components as needed to facilitate client environment communications with proprietary software.

Consultant, MTC Inc (now Aegis Factory)

July 2007 - October 2010

Troubleshoot any problems that arise with field or local personnel concerning stand-alone and network based applications. Coordinate software updates for PCs both in stores and attached to the LAN at corporate locations. Manage preventative maintenance schedule for deployed hardware, insuring internal personnel serviced hardware as contracts dictated. Coordinate new retail location rollout including configuring all hardware and software, delivery of equipment, wiring of site to supply connectivity, on site setup of hardware, testing and verification of hardware on site, and training of customer staff with both in house personnel and contractors. Manage purchasing hardware and software to maintain hardware contracts while keeping an eye towards profitability. Interview, hire, and manage support staff responsible for servicing locations in nine states. Train new hires for the east coast to be self-sufficient technicians working from home offices with little supervision including SLA requirements, call escalation procedures, proper time management, phone etiquette, and service expectations. Audit technician's time cards and trouble ticket closure reports, report to upper management, and develop strategy to make improvements where necessary. Follow up with clients on an ongoing basis to insure satisfaction levels are as high as possible. Meet with client side decision makers weekly to verify satisfaction, identify internal shortcomings, and develop plan to make course corrections where needed. Develop wiki resource for technicians to reference for common issues and develop printed manual for proprietary software products as needed.

Desktop Support Specialist, Source Medical Solutions (now Surgical Information Systems) November 2005 - July 2007

Configure laptops and tablet PCs for use in demonstrating proprietary healthcare software. Troubleshoot any pc issues for internal staff as well as remote sales staff via in person, phone, e-mail, and ticket tracking system. Maintain stock of PCs and peripherals for new employees and to be used as replacements for current employees. Coordinate software updates for both desktops and laptops to insure most current software versions are being used. Assist with network administration duties. Maintain inventory of all computer based assets. Assist in troubleshooting new revisions to proprietary software. Assist with training salespeople with new revisions for existing Source Medical Software products.

Senior Store Support Technician / Customer Service Representative, Books-A-Million August 2003 - November 2005

Repair/replace any and all hardware components of PCs and register systems located within Books-A-Million's 200 store chain. Support users on the LAN at corporate headquarters as well as several satellite administrative facilities via phone and e-mail. Troubleshoot any problems that arise w/field or local personnel concerning stand-alone and network based applications. Assist in network administration duties. Develop databases to track hardware inventory using Access. Install networking hardware in stores as well as troubleshoot network problems at LAN sites. Answer overflow calls for helpdesk during peak hours. Document all processes and procedures related to my job role in preparation for Sarbanes-Oxley compliance.

Technician, United States Postal Service (Teksystems/Dyncorp) - Contract September 1999 - April 2004

Repair/replace any and all hardware components of PCs located in post offices around the state of Alabama. Support users on the 300+ user LAN of the District Office via phone, e-mail, and ticketing system. Build and configure new PCs for general use as well as specialized systems at dozens of postal facilities. Coordinate software updates for standalone PC in field offices. Address compatibility issues that arise between proprietary USPS software and commercial software. Troubleshoot telecommunication and connectivity issues within buildings that postal locations are housed. Assist in minor network administration duties. Develop database to track phone lines in all postal facilities in the Alabama district. Install networking hardware and configure including switches, routers, hubs, etc. Help define, expand, and maintain LANs, including data and voice integration.

CURRENT/PAST CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner Certified Novell Administrator CompTIA A+ Certification

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree, Information Technology / Software Engineering, GPA 3.84 University of Phoenix , March 2009 – May 2011

Associate Degree, Information Technology, GPA 3.87 University of Phoenix , March 2007 - March 2009

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Python, Java, JavaScript, HTML, .Net, PowerShell scripting, PHP, CSS

Cloud/Virtualization Technologies

Amazon Web Services, Docker, Kubernetes, VMWare, Virtual PC, Git, Terraform, Azure

Database Technologies

Microsoft SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Amazon RDS, Amazon DynamoDB

Other Tools

Microsoft, Apple, Linux operating systems - ticketing systems: Remedy ARS, Jira, Zendesk – Remote tools: Connectwise, VNC, RDP, Bomgar

REFERENCES

Martin Fischer

205-936-3144 · martin@vinesauto.com · co-worker while employed with Books-A-Million

Casey Phillips

205-503-3151 · caseyphillips@gmail.com · co-worker while contracting with MTC, Inc

Andrew Morrow

678-787-3449 beardedmongo@gmail.com personal friend and full stack developer I've collaborated with on hobby projects